

Los Angeles, CA / 714-334-5006 / acheng1230@gmail.com / linkedin.com/in/alex-cheng / github.com/acheng1230

PROFILE

I am an experienced data professional, specializing in Python programming. My experience as a Management Consultant has exposed me to a fast-paced environment in constant communication with corporate leadership. As a former Data Analyst, I have developed a knack for technical analysis and visual storytelling to clearly communicate my findings. I strive to be a Data Scientist and relish the opportunity to use data to contribute to a winning organization.

PROJECTS

DATA QUALITY SERVICE DESK / KPMG LLP / DATA STRATEGY & OPERATIONS

Stood up an IT Service Management operating model, framework, and processes for proactively detecting data quality issues, coordinating issue triage and resolution across teams, and automating reporting for management.

#WECOUNTERHATE AD CAMPAIGN / WECOUNTERHATE.COM / HATE SPEECH CLASSIFIER WITH IBM WATSON

Trained IBM Watson to detect hate speech on Twitter, and rebuff the author with a donation to a non-profit organization.

AMAZON REVIEWS SOCIAL LISTENING WITH NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING

Utilized Natural Language Processing to parse Amazon reviews to model topics, as well as sentiment and emotion.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR ASSOCIATE, MANAGEMENT CONSULTING / KPMG LLP / LOS ANGELES, CA / MAY 2018 - JAN. 2020

At a global investment management firm, built out their Data Strategy & Operations department with an emphasis on Enterprise Data Quality. Instrumental in standing up a IT Service Management framework for data quality in addition to projects such as machine learning for data quality, database profiling, and process optimization with automation.

DATA ANALYST / POSSIBLE WORLDWIDE / LOS ANGELES, CA / MAY 2017 - MAY 2018

Developed data science tools and deliverables for clients and internal teams. Spearheaded the utilization of IBM Watson machine learning to deliver cognitive insights. Forecasted user trends with Time Series Analysis. Scraped Amazon reviews and modeled user topics. Implemented ad operations and analytics on client websites. Automated client reporting.

E-COMMERCE & DIGITAL MARKETING SPECIALIST / PEPPER GATE FOOTWEAR INC. / JAN. 2016 - NOV. 2016

Successfully re-platformed digital flagship store, <u>AlegriaShoes.com</u>, resulting in higher traffic and conversion on all channels, especially in mobile. Focused on improving digital marketing, customer experience, and customer retention.

JUNIOR ANALYST / PLEXUS CONSULTING GROUP / WASHINGTON, DC / SEPT. 2013 - DEC. 2013

Restructured a certification program for the Council of Engineering and Scientific Society of Executives. Recommended strategic initiatives for the Salvation Army of Maryland. Responsible for market research, deliverables for internal teams.

EDUCATION

Udacity / Data Scientist Nanodegree / May 2020 - Aug. 2020
General Assembly / Santa Monica, CA / Data Science Immersive / Dec. 2016 - Mar. 2017
Cornell University / Ithaca, NY / Bachelor of Arts, Economics / 2011 - 2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Python / SQL / HTML / CSS

Data Visualization Tableau / PowerBI / Matplotlib / Seaborn / Plotly

Frameworks & Platforms Informatica Data Quality / Collibra Data Governance / Alteryx / Bootstrap / Flask **Ad Operations & Analytics** Google Tag Manager & Analytics / Adobe Analytics / Spredfast / Crimson Hexagon